他们为大家表演一个小品
They will perform a comedy sketch for everyone
名字叫
It's called
（主持人名）
(Host Name)
别报别报
Don't announce it!
什么
What?
演员还没到呢
The actor hasn't arrived yet
这怎么办呢
What should we do now?
这闹的
What a mess
是不是能给个顺序
Could we rearrange the order a bit
上下给颠倒一下
Maybe switch the sequence around
那节目都乱了
Then the whole program would be thrown into chaos
咱们是电影演员之间
We're all film actors here
互相去通融一下
Let's help each other out a little
你这怎么电影演员
What kind of film actor are you
怎么要就要走后门
Why are you trying to use the back door
演员到底应该没有到
So the actor really hasn't arrived
我听见了
I heard that
演员没有到
The actor hasn't arrived
演员没到
The actor isn't here
演员没到找一找
The actor isn't here? Go look for him
我先回去麻烦您可以找一下
I'll head back first. Please try to find him
我去找找找
I'll go look for him
在什么地方
Where is he
不远就在八达岭
Not far. He's at Badaling." (Note: Badaling is where the Great Wall is located, ages away from the Spring Festival Gala studio.)
八达岭我上哪找去
Badaling? How am I supposed to find him there?
我说啊
Listen...
这有一个呢
Here's someone
师傅
Sir
咱们这怎么着
What's going on here
缺演员是怎么着
Do you need an actor?
缺演员
We are short of actors
三位师傅
Sir
你们看我怎么样
what do you think of me
我自己觉着还 还不错
To be honest, I think I'm not bad
行了你
Oh, Come on
你干什么的
What do you do for a living
你要干什么
What are you up to
拍电影嘛
Making movies, right
不就是吃吃喝喝玩玩乐
Isn't it just eating, drinking, and having fun
游山玩水
traveling and sightseeing
哎 同志同志
Hey, comrade, comrade
你想拍电影吗
Do you want to be in a movie
想啊 我都不认
Of course I do
你想拍电影 你别那么说
Don't put it that way
拍电影那是一件工作呢
Making films is a job
是 艰苦的革命工作
A tough revolutionary job
你不想拍吗
You don't want to do it
你想拍，你拍
You want to do it
这就是导演
He is the director
导演师傅 您好 您好
Sir! Hello, sir! Nice to meet you
您抽烟 我刚那买的宇宙牌香烟
Have a cigarette. I just bought this pack
我不收
I can't accept that
No, I really can't
那我就先收着了
Then I'll keep it myself
让他试试
Give him a chance
让我试试啦
Just let me give it a try
那太好了
Wonderful
下面请看小品
And now, please enjoy the sketch
吃面
"Eat Noodles"
你演过电影吗
Have you ever acted in a movie
我，啊...那个《少林寺红牡丹》
Well, there's The Red Peony of Shaolin Temple...（Note: A made-up Kung Fu title）
《火烧圆明园》 《南征北战》
The Burning of the Imperial Palace, From Victory to Victory...(Note: A massive historical epic)
《风雨下钟山》
Storm over Zhongshan...(Note: Serious war classics)
不不不
No, no, no
我问你演过什么角色吗
I mean, have you ever acted in one
角色
Acted?
没演过
No
我都看过
But I've seen them all
都看过
Every single one
我是电影就看
If it's a movie, I would watch it
我是个电影迷
I am a fan of movies
导演
Sir
你一定得答应我这个电影热爱者的这么一点起码的要求
You have to grant one small request from a movie lover
让我也出出名
Let me be famous too
什么
What
出名
Become famous
我们电影工作是革命工作的一个组成部分
Our film work is an integral part of the revolutionary cause
是为人民服务的
In service of the people
你怎么那是出名的机会呢
How can you think it's about becoming famous
对对对
correct, correct
我刚才是说走口了
It was a slip of the tongue
我就是这个意思
This is exactly what I mean
让给 给我呢
Please let me..
也有这么一个为革命工作的机会
a chance to contribute as well
好
Alright
就是吃面
All you'll do is eat noodles
吃面
Eat noodles?
你看
Look
这是一碗面
Here's a bowl of noodles
我今天正好没吃饭
What perfect timing, I'm actually starving
你说什么
What did you say
我说我今天一定好好干
I said I'll do my best
来来来
Come come
一定好好干
I'll do my very best
好了我们各部门都注意了
Alright, everyone, pay attention
化妆服妆道具都准备
Makeup, costumes, props, get ready.
打卤面
Noodles with Meat Gravy
摄影机的位置
Camera position
咱们可以再稍微暗一点
Let's make it a little darker
稍微记一下
Note a bit
好
Good
好嘞
Alright
什么声音
What's that Sound
安静
Quiet on set
诶 照明组
Hey, lighting group
咱们这个演员的表演器在这儿
Our actor’s marks are right here
光 光这儿呢
Keep the lights right here
好嘞 好嘞
Got it, got it
好好
Good, good
什么声
What is that sound
安静
Silence
别笑
Stop laughing
咱们各部分都加紧准备啊
Everyone, speed up the preparations
这一段演员的戏是
Now, the actor’s scene for this part is...
你怎么给吃上了
Why are you already eating it?!
不瞒您说 我今早饭就没吃
To be honest with you, I didn't even have breakfast today
我先垫个底儿
I'm just putting a baseline down
这还没开拍呢
We haven't even started filming yet!
没关系 我看那儿还一捅呢
It's fine. I see you’ve got a whole bucket over there anyway
这段戏是这个样子的
The scene goes like this:
你和你的女朋友已经约好了
You and your girlfriend have a date
今晚八点钟一起看电影
To see a movie together at 8:00 PM tonight
哦 恋爱戏
Oh, a romance scene
现在是
And now it is...
导演 我从小就喜欢看恋爱的电影
Sir, I've loved watching romance movies since I was a kid
你别啰嗦
Stop babbling
现在已经八点钟了
It is already 8:00 PM
八点了
8:00 PM
你正在吃面
You are in the middle of eating your noodles
你的女朋友来叫你
Your girlfriend comes to call for you
你吃完了面放下完就跑出
You finish your noodles, put down the bowl, and run out...
放下碗就跑出
Put down and run out...
就这点词啊
Are these the only lines
哎
Yeah
一共两句词
Just two lines in total
两句词
Two lines
哎
Yeah
你着什么急吗
What's your rush
我不着急
I'm not rushing
我说一共两句台词
I said, there are only two lines in total
你着什么急
What's your rush
是，一共两句台词
Yes, just two lines
我不着急
I am not rushing
不是
No, that's not it...
我说的是一共两句台词
What I am saying is, "There are only two lines in total!"
对啊
Right
你着什么急
What's your rush?
我真的不着急
I really am not rushing
导演
Sir
我说一共两句台词
I'm telling you: "There are only two lines in total!"
你着什么...
What's your...
两句台词我着什么急
I know just two lines, so why the hell should I rush?!
好了
Alright, alright!
你别说话！
Shut up and stop talking!
哎 是
Uh, yes sir
你别说
Don't say a word
我不说
I won't
一共两句台词
There are only two lines in total...
是你说的
...is what YOU are supposed to say!
你着什么急嘛
"What's your rush?"
你等我一会儿嘛
"Just wait for me for a bit."
哦 我好像明白了
Oh I think I get it now
啊
Ah
是我说的
Those are my lines!
你说的
Your lines
你说一遍, 我听听
Try them once, let me hear it.
啊
Ah
说一遍
Say them once?
啊
Ah
就这么说
Just deliver them like that
当然就带情绪了
With the feeling, of course
哦 带点情绪
Ah, with a bit of feeling
哎 你着什么急 等我一会儿
"Hey, what's your rush? Wait for me for a bit!"
这个意思
Which means...
你已经晚了
You are already late
要表现出来那种歉意感
You need to show a sense of apologetic regret
歉意感
A sense of apologetic
apologetic...
对
Exactly
哎，着什么急
"What's your rush?"
等我一会儿
"Wait a bit"
哎 你要边吃边说
You have to say it while eating
你要边吃边说
You must say it while eating
这种意思
Like this vibe
你着什么急
"What's your rush?"
你真的盛碗面
You should actually dish up a real bowl of noodles
找点吃面的感觉
Get into the zone of actually eating noodles
真的？
For real?
还要我吃一碗啊
I get another bowl?!
哎，哎，盛满
Okay，Fill it up
我们各部门都注意了
Attention, all departments!
看一下演员的戏
Prepare for the actor's performance rehearsal
马上就开拍
We will roll immediately.
好
Good
来
Alright, lets go
预备
ready
您先吃
You eat first, please
那我就不客气
Okay, don't mind if I start
来 开始
And... Action!
说 着什么急
Say it! "What's your rush"
吃的要猛啊
Eat like you're starving
要猛 要猛
starving, starving
行
Okay!
没问题
No problem!
说 你着什么急
Say it! "What's your rush?"
台词 说你着什么急
Your line! Say, "What's your rush?"
等一会儿
"Hold on a second!"
吃 要猛
Eat! Fiercely
越猛能够表达人性的
The more fiercely you eat, the more it reflects human nature...
越能够
The more it can...
越能够表达出现
The more it can manifest...
一会儿把我把你当过来
In a moment, I will bring you—you bring yourself over here...
你当过来
You come over here
好 把我把你当过来
Good, I'll bring you—you bring yourself over
放 把它放下
Put it... put it down
放一下 放一下
Put it down! Put it down!
跑出去
Run away!
跑跑跑
And run, run, run!
跑
run!
回来
Come back!
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
味道不错
Delicious
什么味道不错
What do you mean, "Delicious"?
面条 咸淡正好
The noodles. The saltiness is just right
我没问你这个
I didn't ask you about that!
我问你这个
I am asking you about this..
感觉怎么样
...how do you feel?
饱了
Full
这全拧了
It's all totally messed up!
不拧
Not at all
我问你刚才这段戏的感觉怎么样
I am asking how you felt about your acting
戏的感觉
The acting?
戏...没什么感觉
The acting... didn't feel much of anything about the acting
这怎么都没感觉呢 这个戏
How can you have no feeling at all for this scene
我就感觉味还不错
I just felt the flavor was quite nice
别的没有
Nothing else
好了
Alright
对你要求也不能太高感觉
I shouldn't expect more from you
不不不 导演
No, no, no, Sir
咱们这么说吧
Let's put it this way:
您一定得严格要求我
You absolutely must hold me to the strictest standards
这个您看着我哪不合适
Wherever you think I'm not behaviour...
您批评我
...you criticize me!
您骂我
scold me!
您打我都行
Even beat me! Anything is fine
只要能出名
As long as I can get famous...
我又说走口了
Whoops, slip of the tongue again
只要咱们都是为工作嘛, 是不是
As long as we're both doing it for the work, right?
好了好了
Fine, fine
来吧
Lets try again
你盛面吧
Dish up the noodles
盛面
Dish 'em up
盛面盛面
Dishing up, dishing up!
就这一碗了吧
This is the final bowl, right?
真是你开始盛面
Dish 'em up!
太好了
okay
好了我们各部门都注意了啊
Alright, attention all departments!
正式开拍
Official take!
好了吗
Are we ready?
好
Ready
Good
盛满
Fill it to the brim
对
Okay
好好
Good, good
蹲一下
Squat down a bit
Squat down
蹲一下
蹲一点
A bit lower
半蹲一点
A bit of a half-squat
好
Good
正式拍
Official take
正式拍啊
This is an official take
预备
Ready
好
Good
高兴点
Happier
高兴
Happy
自然一点
Be more natural
您看这还自然嘛
Do you think this looks natural enough?
这这怎么样啊
How about this
好了
Fine
你这边感觉要放松啊
You need to loosen up yourself here!
放松不然你开拍就这样
Relax. Otherwise, you'll look stuck like this when we shoot
放松放松放松
Relax, relax, relax.
你饿的吗
Are you hungry?
我松大发了
I overdid it
你主要是啊
Your main issue is..
要感觉上的放松
...you need an internal relaxation
找着那个放松的感觉
Seeking for being relaxed
好了
Enough!
就这么拍了
Keep it that way
Just shoot it like this
你就记住
Just remember:
不要有故意演戏的感觉就行了
As long as you don't look like you're deliberately acting, you're fine
就是要没感觉
Acting like "no feeling"
没感觉
No feeling
来了
Here we go
正式拍
Offical Take!
预备
Ready
开始
Action!
吃面
Eat the noodles!
吃
Eat it!
吃的要猛
Eat like a beast!
说
Say!
Say it!
说
没感觉
"No feeling!"
停
Cut!
说
Say it!
什么没感觉啊
What do you mean, "no feeling"?!
no feeling...
什么没感觉啊
What do you mean exactly
您说的没感觉
You told me to say "no feeling"!
台词是什么
What is your line?!
台词是你着什么急
The line is, "What's your rush..."
你
You...!
导演 您也别批评我了
Sir please don't criticize me anymore
我再吃一碗
I eat another bowl
好 来 坐好
Okay, come, Sit there
坐
Sit
讲出来
Split out!
预备
Ready
高兴点 自然一点
Look happier. Be more natural.
开拍
Action!
摄影机，注意
Camera, attention
说 说词
Say, say the line!
说词 词
The line! The line!
词 词
Line! Line!
台词 词
The line! The line!
词
The line...
说
Say!
行了
Enough!
你
You...
我
I...
怎么了
What's wrong?
我
I...
盛面吧
Dish up the noodles
还
Eat...
还吃啊
Eat more...
快盛面
Hurry, dish 'em up.
感觉不错呀
I feel not bad
盛满
Fill it up
你这个人吃面要吃满碗的
You always finish the bowl up, don't you?
差不多就行了
I think it is enough...
哎 不不不
Oh, no, no, no!
导演 导演够了
Sir, sir, that's enough!
导演 导演,我我我我 实在是不行了
Sir,sir, I-I really can't take any more
好好
Okay, okay
这怎么 这怎么吃的了
How-how can I possibly eat this
蹲好蹲好蹲好
Squat here
蹲下蹲下蹲下
Squat down
蹲下
蹲下啊
Squat down!
蹲不下去了
I can't squat down anymore...
哎呀
Oh, dear...
那个道具
Props group
来来来
Come, come, come
给个凳子
Bring a stool over
对对对
Yes, yes, yes
拿个凳子
Grab a stool
来
Here
谢谢
Thank you
Thank you...
好了
Alright
摄影机，准备
Camera, ready
好
Ready
正式拍
Official take
预备
Ready!
开始
Action!
吃面啊
Eat the noodles!
吃得要猛啊
Eat fiercely!
吃得要猛
对，对
exactly,exactly
吃得要猛
Eat fiercely!
说词啊
Say your line!
你着什么 ... [打嗝]
"What's your...[Hiccup]"
停
Cut!
你能不能
Can you please...
行吧
Fine
[打嗝]
[Hiccup]
好好好
Fine, fine, fine
[打嗝]
[Hiccup]
坚持一下 坚持一分钟 [打嗝] 好不好
Hang in there. Just stick it out for one minute [Hiccup], okay?
一分钟
One minute...
一分钟就一分钟
One minute it is
各部门注意
All departments, attention!
好了来，正式拍
Alright, come, official take!
预备
Ready
[打嗝]
[Hiccup]
我说你
I'm telling you...
导演
Sir...
我实在
I really [Hiccup]...
实在是 [打嗝] 是不行了
...really [Hiccup] can't do this anymore!
你爱找谁[打嗝]找谁
You can find [Hiccup] whoever else you want!
我还是 [打嗝]
I'm going back to [Hiccup]...
干我的
my old...
老本行
Job...
你回来回来
Come back, come back
[打嗝]...现在已经不大想出名了
[Hiccup]... I don't want to be famous anymore
你不想出名也不行啊
You don't even have a choice; you're gonna be a star!
向在座的观众朋友们
To our wonderful audience here tonight...
拜个年吧
Wish a Happy New Year!
哦 这么回事啊
Oh, so that's what this was all about!